Lester Horton Dance Theater Collection
Music Division, Library of Congress
- Publicity, 1926-1996 (Box 10, Box 11, Box-folder 66/1-4, Box-folder 67/1-4, Map-case Map A-3/3)
  The publicity materials in the Collection include news clippings, press releases, promotional material, and posters. The news clippings are arranged chronologically by year, and include previews, reviews, and interviews. They date from 1926 to 1996, with the majority dated from the 1930s through the 1950s. The press releases span the years 1948 to 1958 and consist mostly of typewritten drafts and carbon copies. They were primarily generated by Frank Eng to publicize Dance Theater performances, company members and students, and school activities. The promotional materials are comprised of handwritten, typewritten and printed items such as mailers, fliers, advertisements, and posters about Horton and his various dance groups, Dance Theater performances, school activities, and Horton alumni activities.
  Arranged chronologically.
  - Clippings, 1926-85, 1992-96, n.d. (Box-folder 10/1-28)
  - Posters (Box-folder 66/1)
  - Posters (Box-folder 67/1-4)
  - Posters (Map-case Map A-3/3)
  - Press releases, 1948-58, n.d. (Box-folder 11/1-6)
  - Promotional materials and advertisements, Contents: 1936-92, n.d. (BOX: 11/7-9) 1937-68, n.d. (BOX: 66/2-4) (Box-folder 11/7-9, Box-folder 66/2-4)
- Programs, 1927-1996, undated (Box 12, Box-folder 68/1-5)
  The programs in the Collection consist of original and photocopy versions of typewritten and printed programs of performances by Horton and his dance groups, by others of Horton works, and by Horton alumni. The programs are arranged chronologically and date from 1927 to 1996. Included are several programs of events connected with the Horton Collection, such as the photograph exhibit at Long Beach State University in 1984 and the reconstruction of Horton works at American University in 1996.
  - 1927-35 (Box-folder 12/1)
  - 1936-37 (Box-folder 12/2)
  - 1938-48 (Box-folder 12/3)
  - 1949-51 (Box-folder 12/4)
  - 1929-51 (Box-folder 68/1)
  - 1952 (Box-folder 12/5)
  - 1953 (Box-folder 12/6)
  - 1953 (Box-folder 68/2)
  - 1954 (Box-folder 12/7)
  - 1954 (Box-folder 68/3)
  - 1955 (Box-folder 12/8)
  - 1956-57 (Box-folder 12/9)
  - 1958-59 (Box-folder 12/10)
  - 1959 (Box-folder 68/4)
  - 1960-69 (Box-folder 12/11)
  - 1973-84 (Box-folder 12/12)
  - 1996 (Box-folder 12/13)
  - Undated (Box-folder 12/14)
  - Undated (Box-folder 68/5)
- Music, 1918-1958 (Box 13-22)
  The music series consists of holograph manuscripts and printed music scores of original music and arrangements that were used primarily for performance and teaching. The materials date from 1918 to 1958 and are arranged alphabetically by title.
  Arranged alphabetically by title.
  - 14 traditional Spanish songs from Texas: transcribed by Gustavo Durán. Washington, D.C.: Pan American Union, 1942., Printed score with lyrics; On t.p.: From recordings; Also on t.p.: Music Series, No. 4; April 1942 (Box-folder 13/1)
  - Aesthetic ecstasy, Holograph manuscript for piano in pencil; 1 p.; Music by Lou Harrison; Note: Used in Something to please everybody (Box-folder 13/2)
  - Artistry in bolero. New York: Leslie Music Corporation, 1947., Music by Pete Rugolo; Printed piano-conductor score and parts; 2 copies; On t.p.: Recorded on Capitol Records by Stan Kenton in Album BD-39 (Box-folder 13/3)
  - Artistry in boogie. New York: Leslie Music Corporation, 1947., Music by Stan Kenton and Pete Rugolo; Printed piano-conductor score and parts; On t.p.: Recorded on Capitol Record No. 273 (Box-folder 13/4)
  - Artistry in percussion. New York: Leslie Music Corporation, 1947., Music by Pete Rugolo; Printed parts; Copyist's manuscript of bass part (Box-folder 13/5)
  - Artistry jumps. New York: Robbins Music Corporation, 1946., Music by Stan Kenton; Printed piano-conductor score and parts; On t.p.: Capitol Record No. 229 (Box-folder 13/6)
  - Babalú. New York: Peer International Corporation, 1939., Music by Margarita Leocuna; Spanish lyrics by Margarita Leocuna; English lyrics by S. K. Russell; Printed piano-conductor score and parts (Box-folder 13/7)
  - Barrel house, Music by Anita Short; Photocopy of manuscript score with holograph annotations; 8 p.; On cover page: December 1947 (Box-folder 13/8)
  - Beguine, Manuscript full score in pencil; 10 p.; Manuscript parts in ink (Box-folder 13/9)
  - Beguine, Manuscript part in ink (Box-folder 13/10)
  - The beloved, Manuscript for piano in ink; 10 p.; Music by Judith Hamilton; After composer's name: 1948 (Box-folder 14/1)
  - The beloved, Manuscript for piano in ink with annotations in pencil; 11 p.; Manuscript sketches in pencil; 4 p.; Music by Judith Hamilton (Box-folder 14/2)
  - Bim biri ho - Cuba antigua, Manuscript parts in ink with annotations in pencil; Music by [Ramón Márquez and Salvador Rangel] (Box-folder 14/3)
  - Bim biri ho, Manuscript parts in pencil (Box-folder 14/4)
  - Bim biri ho: Mambo. Mexico: Hnos Márquez, S. de R.L., 1952., Music by Ramón Márquez and Salvador Rangel; Printed parts with annotations in pencil (Box-folder 14/5)
  - Bizet has his day. New York: Mutual Music Society, Inc., 1942., Arranged by Ben Homer; Printed piano-conductor score and parts; On cover page: based on Bizet's L'Arlesienne Suite (Box-folder 14/6)
  - Blue flame. New York: Charling Music Corp., 1943., Music by James Noble and Joe Bishop; Lyric by Leo Corday; Printed piano-conductor score and parts with annotations in pencil (Box-folder 14/7)
  - Blue snow. New York: Leeds Music Corporation, 1943., Music by Milt Lance; Printed short score and parts; On cover page: Leeds original manuscript series (Box-folder 14/8)
  - Boogie woogie. New York: Melrose Music Corp., 1943., Printed piano-conductor score and parts; On cover page: Arranged by Deane Kincaide for Tommy Dorsey and his orchestra onVictor Record No. 26054 (Box-folder 14/9)
  - Brown County, Indiana, Manuscript piano part in ink; 12 p.; Music by Kenneth Klausss; On cover page: Lorca (Brown County) (Box-folder 14/10)
  - Brown County, Indiana, Photocopy of manuscript two piano part with annotations in pencil; 16 p.; After composer's name: 1950 (Box-folder 14/11)
  - Brown County, Indiana, Photocopy of manuscript two piano part; 16 p.; After composer's name: April 11, 1950; 2 copies (Box-folder 14/12)
  - Brush off [blues], Photocopy of manuscript for piano; Music by Milton Rosen and Laird Mason; 2 copies; Note: Used in On the upbeat (Box-folder 14/13)
  - Burla del unicornio, Manuscript for two piano part in ink; 14 p. (Box-folder 14/14)
  - Caballo negro. Mexico: Editorial Mexicana de Música Internacional S.A., 1951., Printed parts with holograph annotations in pencil (Box-folder 14/15)
  - Caballo negro., Manuscript piano-conductor score; 2 p.; Manuscript parts (Box-folder 14/15)
  - Cholito the flop, Manuscript short score; 3 p.; Manuscript parts; On p. 1: Cholito - The Flop (Revised) (Box-folder 14/16)
  - Chôros No. 5. Brazil: Ediçao da Casa Vieira Machado de Guilherme Fontainha, n.d., Music by Heitor Villa-Lobos; Printed for piano with annotations in pencil; On t.p.: Alma Brasileira; Rio, 1925 (Box-folder 15/1)
  - Chronicle, Manuscript parts in pencil; Music by Sidney Cutner (Box-folder 15/2)
  - Chronicle, Manuscript. sketches in pencil; [30] p. (Box-folder 15/3)
  - Closing, Manuscript for piano in ink with annotations in pencil; 2 p.; Music by Lou Harrison (Box-folder 15/4)
  - Danse Congo, Manuscript sketches in pencil; [8] p.; Music by Sidney Cutner (Box-folder 15/5)
  - Dedication to Ruth, Mary, Martha, Manuscript piano score in ink; 10 p.; Music by Gertrude Rivers Robinson; On t.p. under composer's name: 1953; Also referred to as To Ruth, Mary and Martha; Note: Used in Dedications in our time (Box-folder 15/6)
  - Dithyrambos, Manuscript piano part in pencil; 3 p.; Manuscript percussion part in pencil; 2 p.; Music by Lou Harrison (Box-folder 15/7)
  - The Elks' parade. New York: Robbins Music Corporation, 1942., Music by Bobby Sherwood; Printed piano-conductor score and parts with annotations in pencil (Box-folder 15/8)
  - Five little dances for the piano. New York: G. Schirmer, Inc., 1946., Music by Paul Creston; Printed for piano (Box-folder 15/9)
  - Five pieces on popular Brazilian children's songs. New York: Music Press, Inc., n.d., Music by Heitor Villa-Lobos; Printed for piano; On t.p.: Album 6; On t.p.: A William Kapell (Box-folder 15/10)
  - Five pieces on popular Brazilian children's songs. New York: Music Press, Inc., n.d., Music by Heitor Villa-Lobos; Printed for piano; On t.p.: Album 7; On t.p.: A Noemi Bittencourt (Box-folder 15/11)
  - Flight from reality, Manuscript sketch in ink and pencil; 7 p.; Music by Dane Rudhyar (Box-folder 15/12)
  - Frevo, Manuscript parts in ink with annotations in pencil; Music by Milton Rosen; Note: Used in Tropic trio and/or Estilo de tú (Box-folder 15/13)
  - Get happy - fox trot. New York: Remick Music Corp., 1930., Music by Harold Arlen and Ted Koehler; Printed piano-conductor score and parts (Box-folder 15/14)
  - Growth of Action, Holograph manuscript score in ink; 3 p.; Music by Dane Rudhyar; Note: Under composer's name: From "Song from Exile" 1926-27 (Box-folder 15/15)
  - The house on the hill: A madrigal cantata, Photocopy of manuscript chorus score; 20 p.; Music by Michael Hennagin; On t.p.: From poem manuscript by Edwin Arlington Robinson (Box-folder 15/16)
  - The hundred best short classics. London: Paterson's Publications Ltd., n.d., Music by various composers; Printed for piano (Box-folder 15/17)
  - Ican. New York: Mills Music Inc., 1954., Music by Eddie Cano; Printed for piano; On cover page: Recorded by The Tony Martínez Quintet on RCA-Victor Records (Box-folder 15/18)
  - I'll never be free. New York: Laurel Music Corp., 1950., Music by Bennie Benjamin and George Weiss; Printed piano-conductor score and parts (Box-folder 15/19)
  - Inebria, Manuscript sketch in pencil; 2 p.; Music by Lou Harrison (Box-folder 15/20)
  - Jalousie, Photocopy violin part with annotations in ink; Music by Jacob Gade (Box-folder 15/21)
  - Jungle river boat, Arranger's holograph score in pencil; 10 p.; Arranger's holograph parts in ink; Arranged by Michael Hennagin (Box-folder 16/1)
  - Latino. Mexico: Editorial Mexicana de Música Internacional, S.A., 1951., Music by Pérez Prado; Printed parts (Box-folder 16/2)
  - Leap frog. New York: Leeds Music Corporation, 1942., Music by Joe Garland; Printed condensed score and parts with annotations in ink (Box-folder 16/3)
  - Look to the rainbow. New York: Crawford Music Corporation, n.d., Music by Burton Lane; Printed for piano (Box-folder 16/4)
  - A lost soul in outer space, no. 1, op. 7, Manuscript; [?] p.; Music by Robert M. Ada; Printed for piano (Box-folder 16/5)
  - Love dance-cumbia, Arranger's holograph score in pencil; 12 p.; Arranged by Michael Hennagin (Box-folder 16/6)
  - Love dance-cumbia, Copyist's manuscript parts in ink with annotations in pencil (Box-folder 16/7)
  - Love dance-cumbia, Copyist's manuscript lead sheet in ink with annotations in ink; 3 p. (Box-folder 16/7)
  - Love dance-cumbia, Copyist's manuscript parts in ink (Box-folder 16/8)
  - Lysistrata, Manuscript sketches in pencil; [45] p.; Music by Simon Abel (Box-folder 16/9)
  - Magic dance for piano and percussion instruments, Photocopy of manuscript score; 9 p.; Music by Ernest Kanitz; On t.p.: Copyright 1947 (Box-folder 16/10)
  - Mambo jambo. New York: Southern Music Pub., Inc., n.d., Music by Pérez Prado; Lyric by Raymond Karl and Charlie Towne; Arranged by Jack Mason; Printed piano-conductor score and parts (Box-folder 16/11)
  - Mambo No. 5. Mexico: Editorial Mexicana de Música Internacional, 1948., Music by Pérez Prado; Printed parts with annotations in pencil; 3 copies (Box-folder 16/12)
  - Mambo #5 - Bamboo Alley, Copyist's manuscript of lead sheet in ink; 2 p.; Copyist's manuscript parts; Original music by Pérez Prado (Box-folder 17/1)
  - Mambo #8, Manuscript with pasted on photocopy of manuscript lead sheet; 1 p.; Manuscript with pasted on photocopy of manuscript of parts (Box-folder 17/2)
  - A manha da pierrete. Providence, R.I.: Axelrod-Music, 1938., Music by Heitor Villa-Lobos; Printed for solo piano (Box-folder 17/3)
  - A mão direita tem una roseira, [S.l.]: [s.n.], n.d.; Music by Heitor Villa-Lobos; Printed for piano (Box-folder 17/4)
  - The matriarch: a ballet for 3 dancers, Holograph manuscript score; 37 p.; Music by Michael Hennagin; At the end: April 27, 58 [1958] (Box-folder 17/5)
  - Medea, Manuscript piano I part in pencil; 10 p.; Manuscript piano II part in pencil; 8 p.; Music by Audrée Covington (Box-folder 17/6)
  - Mintika No.3: From the three Maries. New York: Carl Fischer, Inc., 1941., Music by Heitor Villa-Lobos; Printed for piano with annotations in pencil (Box-folder 17/7)
  - Miscellaneous titles, Contents: Aphrodisiac [used in Something to please everybody] Boogy-woogy Caribbean dance Day feast song Fanfare Hoop dance Jaleo de Jerez Jumpin' at the woodside Lester Horton routine Maguey May dance The merry widow Sing sing sing War dance (Box-folder 17/8)
  - Morning mourning, Photocopy of manuscript for piano with annotations in pencil; 24 p.; Music by Gertrude Rivers Robinson (Box-folder 17/9)
  - Occult, Manuscript sketch in ink and pencil; 1 p.; Music by Lou Harrison (Box-folder 17/10)
  - Old devil moon: Fox trot. New York: Crawford Music Corporation, n.d., Music by Burt Lane; Words by E. Y. Harburg; Printed piano-conductor score and parts with annotations in pencil; On cover page: From the New Musical "Finian's Rainbow" (Box-folder 17/11)
  - Orientale, Manuscript sketches in ink and pencil; [6] p. (Box-folder 17/12)
  - The peanut vendor: Fox trot. New York: Edward B. Marks Music Corporation, 1928., Music by Moises Simons; Lyric by Marion Sunshine and L. Wolfe Gilbert; Arranged by Lawrence Kemptom; Printed piano score (Box-folder 17/13)
  - Prado de Pena see: Yerma
  - A próle do bébé No. 1. - Collecção de 8 peças. Rio de Janeiro: Sampaio Araujo & Cia., n.d., Music by Heitor Villa-Lobos; Printed for piano solo (6 separate parts); Contents: No.2 Moreninha - A boneca de massa No.3 Caboclinha - A boneca de barro No.4 Mulatinha - A boneca de borracha No.5 Negrinha - A boneca de páo No.8 Bruxa - A boneca de panno; Above composer's name: Rio, 1918 (Box-folder 17/14)
  - Que te parece cholito: Tamborera Panameña. Mexico: Editorial Mexicana de Música Internacional, S.A., 1950., Music by Ulpiano Herrera; Arranged by Avelino Muñoz; Printed lead sheet and parts; Manuscript parts; Manuscript with pasted on photocopy of manuscript of parts (Box-folder 17/15)
  - Redskin rumba. New York: Capitol Songs, Inc., n.d., Music by Charlie Barnet; Printed short score and parts (Box-folder 18/1)
  - St. Francis, Manuscript for piano in pencil; 59 p.; Music by Gershen Kingsley; At end of score: June 5, 54 [1954] (Box-folder 18/2)
  - Salome, Manuscript sketches in pencil; [21] p.; Manuscript percussion parts in pencil (Box-folder 18/3)
  - Salome, Copyist's manuscript full score in pencil; 27 leaves (Box-folder 22/1)
  - Salome, Manuscript percussion score in pencil; [70] leaves; Manuscript miscellaneous music sheet: Prophet's Entrance (Box-folder 22/2)
  - Salome, Copyist's manuscript percussion parts in ink; 8 p.; Manuscript percussion parts in pencil (Box-folder 18/4)
  - Salome, Manuscript percussion score in pencil; [69] leaves (Box-folder 22/3)
  - Salome, Manuscript percussion parts in pencil (Box-folder 18/5-7)
  - Salome, Copyist's manuscript percussion score in pencil; 49 leaves (Box-folder 22/4)
  - Salome, Copyist's manuscript parts in ink (Box-folder 18/8)
  - Salome, Manuscript of choreographic-scenario material in pencil; 8 p. (Box-folder 19/1)
  - Salome (Dance to Herod), Manuscript score in pencil in spiral binding; [13] p. (Box-folder 19/2)
  - Seguidilla, Copyist's manuscript for piano I in ink; 4 p.; Copyist's manuscript for piano II in ink; 4 p.; Music by Isaac Albeniz (Box-folder 19/3)
  - Sextette for piano and strings, Copyist's manuscript score in ink; 10 p.; Music by Earl Kim (Box-folder 19/4)
  - Shootin' star, Photocopy of manuscript scores [13 separate scores]; Music by Sol Kaplan; Lyrics by Bob Russell (Box-folder 19/5)
  - Similau. New York: Campbell Music, Inc., 1948., Music by Arden Clar; English lyrics by Harry Coleman; Spanish lyrics by Leopoldo Gonzalez; Printed parts; 2 copies (Box-folder 19/6)
  - Sing sing sing: With a swing. New York: Robbins Music Corporation, 1936., Music by Louis Prima; Lyrics by Louis Prima; Printed piano-conductor score and parts (Box-folder 19/7)
  - Skokiaan: South Africa song: Fox trot. New York: Shapiro, Bernstein & Co., Inc., 1952., Music by August Arurgwa; Arranged by Johnny Warrington; Printed piano-conductor score and parts with annotations in pencil (Box-folder 19/8)
  - La soldadera, Photocopy manuscript for piano; 6 p.; Music by Kenneth Klauss; 2 copies; Note: Under composer's name: Dec 31, 1949 (Box-folder 19/9)
  - La soldadera (Orozco), Manuscript for piano in ink; 6 p.; Music by Kenneth Klauss; Note: Used in Dedications in our time: To José Clemente Orozco (Box-folder 19/10)
  - Something to please everyone, Manuscript in ink and pencil; 2 p.; Music by Lou Harrison (Box-folder 19/11)
  - Stompin' at the savoy. New York: Robbins Music Corporation, 1936., Music by Benny Goodman, Chick Webb and Edgar Sampson; Printed piano-conductor score and parts; Under title: Victor Record No. 25247-A (Box-folder 19/12)
  - Suite for the piano. New York: G. Schirmer, Inc., 1942., Music by George Antheil; Printed for piano (Box-folder 19/13)
  - Temptation. New York: Robbins Music Corporation, 1946., Music by Nacio Herb Brown; Lyrics by Arthur Freed; Printed piano-conductor score and parts (Box-folder 20/1)
  - Things ain't what they used to be, Manuscript score in pencil; 4 p.; Manuscript parts in ink (Box-folder 20/2)
  - Totem incantation, Manuscript piano score in pencil in spiral binding; [32] p.; Manuscript piano score part I in pencil in spiral binding; [16] p.; Manuscript piano score part II in pencil in spiral binding; [12] p.; Music by Judith Hamilton; Manuscript parts in pencil (Box-folder 20/3)
  - Totem incantation, Manuscript score in pencil; [53] leaves (Box-folder 22/5)
  - Totem incantation, Manuscript sketches in ink and pencil (Box-folder 20/4)
  - Tropical merengue. New York: Edward B. Marks Music Corporation, 1955., Music by Rafael Muñoz; Arranged by Joe Loco; English lyrics by Lawrence Elow and Don Marsh; Printed piano-conductor score and parts with annotations in ink (Box-folder 20/5)
  - Trumpet blues and cantabile: Fox trot. New York: Paramount Music Corporation, 1942., Music by Harry Janes and Jack Matthias; Arranged by Jack Matthias; Printed piano-conductor score and parts (Box-folder 20/6)
  - The twelve days of christmas. New York: G. Schirmer, Inc., 1952., Printed piano score; On t.p.: Collected and adapted for voice and piano by John Jacob Niles (Box-folder 20/7)
  - Unidentified, Manuscripts in ink and pencil; Printed for piano (Box-folder 20/8)
  - [Untitled], Manuscript score in pencil; 7 p.; Music by Gerhardt Dorn (Box-folder 20/9)
  - [Untitled], Manuscript for piano in pencil; 4 p.; Music by Heitor Villa-Lobos (Box-folder 20/10)
  - The voice of Haiti. New York: Clarence Williams Music Publishing Co., Inc., 1938., Recompilation by Laura Bowman and Leroy Antoine; On cover page: An unusual collection of original Native ceremonial songs, invocations, voodoo chants, drum beats and rhythm manuscript, stories of traditions, etc. of the Haitian People. (Box-folder 20/11)
  - Warsaw ghetto, Manuscript of choreographic-scenario material; [5] p.; Music by Sol Kaplan (Box-folder 20/12)
  - Xango, Music by Milton Rosen; Manuscript parts in ink; Note: Used in Tropic trio and/or Estilo du tú (Box-folder 21/1)
  - Xango, Copyist's manuscript lead sheet in ink; 9 p.; Copyist's manuscript parts in ink; On t. p. of lead sheet: Concert version (Box-folder 21/2)
  - Xango, Copyist's manuscript lead sheet in ink; 5 p.; Copyist's manuscript parts in ink; On t.p. of lead sheet: Commercial version (Box-folder 21/3)
  - Xango, Copyist's manuscript parts in ink (Box-folder 21/4)
  - Yerma, Manuscript for piano I in pencil; 12 p.; Manuscript for piano II in pencil; 11 p.; Music by Gertrude Rivers Robinson (Box-folder 21/5)
- Photographic Materials, 1930-1965 (Box 23-38, 71)
  The photographic material in the Collection includes photoprints, contact sheets, and negatives, dated roughly from the early 1930s to the early 1960s, with the majority dated in the 1950s. The photoprints and contact sheets are housed together while the negatives are separate; the contact sheets are filed with the predominant subject on the sheet/roll. Within each format, the materials are arranged by subject in the following order: Performance and Publicity, Individuals, Groups, Classroom--Adult, Classroom--Children, Children--performance, and Miscellaneous. Every effort has been made to file the items appropriately. The photoprints are predominantly black and white in a variety of sizes. Subjects in the photographs are often listed on the back. The negatives include originals and copy negatives; photoprints of many of these items are in the Collection.
  Within the photographic material series, the performance and publicity category is arranged alphabetically by title of work, and includes rehearsal, performance, and publicity stills. The photographers, including some well known from the movie industry, were attracted to Horton's work and the activities of the Dance Theater. They include Laurance T. Clark, Constantine Hassalevris, Toyo Miyatake, Howard Morehead, Jerome Robinson, Leo Salkin, Ralph Samuels, and Charles Van Maanen. The classroom category includes workshops and may contain some rehearsal shots. Some of the dancers photographed in the children's classes and productions, such as Carmen de Lavallade and Sondra Orans, went on to become company members.
  Arranged by format and then by subject.
  - Photoprints
    - Performance and Publicity (Box 23-37, 71)
      - 7 scenes with ballabilli (Box-folder 23/1)
      - 7 scenes with ballabilli (Box-folder 32/1)
      - According to St. Francis (Box-folder 23/2)
      - Another touch of Klee (1951) (Box-folder 23/3, 71/1)
      - Another touch of Klee (Box-folder 32/2)
      - Atlantis [film] (Box-folder 23/4)
      - Art patrons (Box-folder 32/3)
      - Aztec ceremonial (Box-folder 23/5)
      - Bal Caribe (Box-folder 23/6)
      - Bal Caribe (Box-folder 32/4)
      - Bamboo alley, bal Caribe (Box-folder 23/7)
      - Barrel house (Box-folder 23/8)
      - The beloved (Box-folder 23/9)
      - Bolero, bal Caribe 1954 (Box-folder 23/10)
      - Bouquet for Molly (1950) (Box-folder 23/11, 71/2)
      - Brown county, Indiana (Box-folder 23/12)
      - Carmen (Box-folder 71/3)
      - Chronicle (Box-folder 24/1)
      - Chronicle (Box-folder 32/5)
      - Chronicle (Box-folder 36/1)
      - Chungsville (Box-folder 24/2)
      - La crèation du monde (Box-folder 24/3)
      - Cuba antigua (Box-folder 24/4, 71/4)
      - Danzón cubano (Box-folder 24/5)
      - Dedications in our time., Contents: Memorial to Hiroshima (BOX: 24/6) To José Clemente Orozco (BOX: 36/2) To José Clemente Orozco (BOX: 24/7) (Box-folder 24/6, Box-folder 36/2, Box-folder 24/7)
      - The empty chair (Box-folder 24/8)
      - Estilo de tú. Frevo [also used in Tropic trio] (Box-folder 24/9)
      - Estilo de tú. Xango [also used in Tropic trio] (Box-folder 24/10)
      - The flop (Box-folder 24/11)
      - The flop (Box-folder 32/6)
      - Frevo (1951) (Box-folder 71/6)
      - Jenny and the bench of the lamb (Box-folder 24/12)
      - Kandyan, bal Caribe 1954 (Box-folder 24/13)
      - Liberian suite (1956) (Box-folder 24/14, 71/7)
      - Liberian suite (1952) (Box-folder 32/7)
      - Liberian suite (Box-folder 36/3)